Emily Davies

504. 435. 4678 ~ emilygdavies42@gmail.com ~ www.linkedin.com/in/emily-davies9/ ~ https://github.com/Scaramouche9

Summary

Data analyst with 10 years of experience developing websites, troubleshooting equipment, and enhancing customer experience. Improved accessibility and responsiveness for clients, increased ticket resolution rate by 30%, and reduced equipment purchases by 10% in 3 months. Orchestrated successful tours with performances at over 100 venues.

Employment

Web Developer, Barnet Associates: Business Technology Consulting; Remote – 2023-present

- Build bespoke websites for clients using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap
- Ensure websites adhere to Google Lighthouse standards, increasing accessibility and responsiveness up to 20% using media queries and developer tools

Java Consultant, Genesis10: Technology Consulting Firm; Remote – 2022-2023

- Developed 9 full-stack and back-end applications using SQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Java, JavaScript, and React
- Tested code thoroughly using Spring Boot unit testing and developer tools

Store Manager, Hollywood Lights: Audiovisual and Theatrical Retailer; Portland, OR – 2022

- Managed storefront, website, and inventory for multi-million dollar commercial lighting and sound retailer
- Drew insights from previous sales data to eliminate unnecessary spending by 10% in 3 months

Owner and member of band, Renshaw Davies; New Orleans, LA – 2012-2021

- Orchestrated booking and promotion of up to three-month tours throughout US and Canada
- Coordinated with over 100 venue owners to ensure successful performances

Office Assistant, mumms Software: Hospice and Palliative Care Solutions; New Orleans, LA – 2019-2020

- Utilized Jira to effectively resolve client tickets or dispatch to the appropriate help desk
- Conducted research and logged contact data for over 50 hospices using Excel to support client acquisition

Audiovisual Technician, New Orleans Convention Center; New Orleans, LA – 2012-2019

- Conducted inventory of 18 storage rooms using Excel to inform new equipment purchases
- Provided reliable support for over 400 shows, troubleshooting audiovisual equipment to ensure client satisfaction

Certifications

IBM Data Analyst Professional Certificate; Coursera, 2023

Projects

Character Sheet Builder

- Collaborated with two teammates to build a MySQL, Java, and JavaScript app that allows users to create characters
- Drafted wireframe using Excalidraw to plan project layout
- Enabled users to upload custom images using Cloudinary

Pokedex

- Constructed JavaScript app using AJAX to retrieve data from an external API, PokeApi
- Utilized Bootstrap to create navigation and modals

Education

Goucher College; Towson, MD - BA Music